Welcome to CS 263 Python for Programmers.
This course is intended as an introduction
to Python for students already familiar
with another language
with an emphasis on C++ over Java.
The overall focus of this course
is to prepare to teach you how to apply
your existing knowledge
to write Python code. Tools of the trade.
In this course, we all use many tools,
including vim, Git, unit testing / test driven development,
pydoc, tox, pycode style / pylint
PlantUML and SDEdit
A few tools
will be used heavily for office hours
and questions.
Zoom for office
hours, email and questions. Yes,
I do realize that I have listed questions
as a tool for answering questions.
As much as I would like
to make a joke about recursion,
this is actually an instance
of the Socratic method.
Lecture examples.
Most lectures
will be based on the review examples.
If you are curious, take a look
at the commit history on GitHub.
The example code is not stagnant.
It is updated every semester.
Questions one: Do I need to know all
the tools listed in tools of the trade?
No, you do not need to know
all the tools.
Two, why do you use them?
The short answer is that Vim works.
I can write code quickly, compile and run
code and switch between languages.
More importantly,
I can do everything completely
from the keyboard without the mouse.
Three.
What is your favorite language?
It is currently a tie
between python and rust,
although it is currently python,
at least for today.
Four.
Can I ask you about a topic
not covered in lecture? Yes.
Five.
Who is Raymond Hettinger?
Raymond Hettinger
is one of the Python core developers.
He is known for his amazing
python talks slash lectures
beginning of the semester concerns
you will hear me discuss
and reference topics from various courses,
including CS 330 Object
oriented design and programing.
CS 361 Data structures and algorithms,
CS 381 discrete structures and CS 417
Computational methods and software.
Every semester, a few students end up
terrified that they have missed
a required prerequisite course.
Before you start second guessing yourself,
take a look at the Prerequisites
section of the syllabus.
If a course is not listed
as a prerequisite, you are not expected
to have completed it.
Why mention other courses?
Computer science is a broad field.
There are many connections
between topics and concepts.
One of the biggest
mistakes anyone can make
is to
treat a course as existing in a vacuum.
This is especially true of teachers
and students.
Remember two things.
One, one of our goals is to learn
how to see these connections
and use them to solidify understanding
in this course and other courses.
I enjoy computer science,
including this course, and I have a
penchant to get carried away.